A Finding Aid to the William P. Daley Papers, 1905-2004 (bulk 1951-2001), in the Archives of American Art AAA.dalewill
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition Files, 1949-1999, undated; Series 3; 2.7 Linear feet Boxes 3-5
  - Auction Files, 1979-1993, undated; 3.2
    Auction Files contain material relating to art auctions for which Daley donated a work of art. Found are correspondence, price lists, printed materials, including catalogs and announcements, and receipts. Files are arranged chronologically by year of auction.
    - Channel 12 Art & Antiques Auction, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Haystack Auction 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - American Craft Museum Selection '85, 1985, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Haystack Silent Auction, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - American Craft Museum Bewitched by Craft, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Clay Studio Ceramic Art Sweepstakes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Christie's, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Wallingford Potters Guild, 1990-1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "Touchstone Auction", 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition Juror Files, 1968-1999; 3.3
    The Exhibition Juror Files contain material concerning exhibitions for which Daley was a juror or critic. Materials in these files are very similar to the Exhibitions files and typically include correspondence, expense lists and receipts, award lists, and printed materials, including announcements, brochures, and press clippings. Files are arranged chronologically by year of exhibition.
    - "York Sate Craft Fair", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Delaware Art Museum Annual Contemporary Crafts Exhibition (1973) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Show of Crafts and Graphics (1978) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Philadelphia Craft Show (1979) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Arts Alive '81, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Michigan Ceramics/Rouge 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Boston University "Certificate of Mastery Exhibition", 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - New Directions in Tile (1983) (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Pennsylvania Guild of Craftsmen (1984) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Designed and Made for Use (1985) (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Market House '86, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Swain School of Design Graduate Exhibition (1986) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Abington Art Center Ceramic Exhibition (1988) (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Main Line Center of the Arts 25th Annual Craft Exhibition (1988), 1988-1999 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - "New Jersey Art Educators As Artists" (1990) (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - National Museum of Ceramic Art First Regional Juried Exhibition (1991) (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Louis Comfort Tiffany Foundation (1991), 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - "Fleischer Art Memorial Challenge Competition" (1992-1993), 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Wallingford Potters Guild (1992) (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Clay Here and There (1993) (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - "Members/Faculty Exhibition" at Perkins Center for the Arts (1994), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Strictly Functional Pottery National Exhibit (1994), 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Smithsonian Craft Show (1995), 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Abington Friends School Celebrate Crafts, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - University of the Arts MFA Winter Critique, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Pew Fellowship in the Arts, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Clay Studio Exhibition (1997), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Ceramics '97, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - 1997 Central Pennsylvania Festival of the Arts, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Wayne Art Center: Craft Forms '98, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Project Files, 1956-2000, undated; Series 4; 1 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  Project Files typically contain correspondence, expense lists, receipts, sketches, printed material, and photographs related to sculpture projects that William Daley completed or proposed during his career. This includes public and private commissions, notably a sculpture for IBM at the Seattle World's Fair, a sculpture for South African Airways, the Fairfield Maxwell Wall, and work completed at the Westminster Presbyterian Church. Files are arranged chronologically by year.
  - Works in Feasterville, Pennsylvania, 1956-1963 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - "Timeless Metronome", 1958 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - "Progeny", circa 1959, 1975, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Casablanca International Trade Fair, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - "Columbine", 1960 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - John Pickett Fountain, circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Robert John Sculpture, circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - IBM at Seattle World's Fair Sculpture, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 61-63)
  - Colgate Research Center Mural, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Ceramic and Teak Wood Screens, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - State University of New York, Fredonia Senior Class Present, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - "Centurian Marker", 1964, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 67-68)
  - Works in Fredonia, New York, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Penn State Planters, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Lillian Garabedian Memorial, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - ARCO Chemical Company Sculpture, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - TAP Portuguese Airways Sculpture, 1966-1968, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Burning Bush", circa 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hallenwall Realty Company Sculpture, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - John Pickett Fireplace, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Haddington Recreation Center Fountain, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - South African Airways Sculpture, 1970-1971, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
  - Germantown Friends School Sculpture, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Fairfield Maxwell Wall, 1971-1979, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12-14)
  - North American Watch Co. Sculpture, circa 1973 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Campbell Soup Tureen, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Our Lady of the Rosary Baptismal Font, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Squire Enterprises, Inc. Flower Pots, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ritz Motion Picture Theatre Sculpture, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 19-21)
  - Certainteed Corp. Fountain, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - NEA "Art in Public Places" Inquiry, 1979, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Earl Millard Pot, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Wills Eye Hospital Wall, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - St. Paul's Episcopal Church Baptismal Font, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Studio Potter Network Drawing, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Arrow International, Inc. Sculpture, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Westminster Presbyterian Church, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
  - Sam Schacht Drawings, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Arrow International, Inc. Wall Segment, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Wayne Bates Dormer, 1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Workshops, Seminars, and Lectures, 1958-1998, undated; Series 5; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 6-8
  This series includes extensive materials on workshops William Daley taught, seminars he participated in, and lectures that he gave on topics of art, ceramics, and education. Files typically contain most or all of the following: correspondence, expense lists and receipts, schedules of events, lecture or teaching notes, printed material, including brochures and press clippings, and photographs of the event. Files are labeled according to location or title of the event and are arranged chronologically by year.
  - NBC's "Adventuring in the Hand Arts", 1958 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - General Motors Summer Program, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - South Senior High School, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - World of Arts Raku Workshop, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Waldorf College, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Collab '71, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - California College of Arts and Crafts, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Montgomery County Community College, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Board of Education and Philadelphia Art Alliance "Artist to Artist Program", 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Ohio State University, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Alfred University, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - "Jam Craft Media Day & Exhibition", 1977 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Arts Council Program, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - William Allen High School, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Philadelphia College of Art's Law and Art Seminar, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Cleveland Institute of Art, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Rhode Island School of Design, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Institute of Contemporary Art, University of Pennsylvania, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - University of Rhode Island, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - NCECA/SuperMud Conference, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Exhibit A: Peter Voulkos Exhibit, 1979, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - University of Pennsylvania "Continuum", 1979 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Drexel University, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Purdue University, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Banff Center Summer Session, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 60-61)
  - Stockton State College, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - "Contemporary American Potter" Symposium, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - NCECA 1980 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Avila College, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - "Ceramics Seminar '81", 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - "International Ceramics Symposium 1981", 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Art Sales and Rental Gallery Talk, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art "Celebration of Crafts", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Manayunk Art Center, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fredonia State University College, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - NCECA 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Consortium: 80/81, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - University of Colorado at Boulder, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Emily Carr College of Art, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Swarthmore College, 1982, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NCECA 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Luther College Artists Visit, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Blossom Festival School Art Program, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - NCECA Boston '84, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Napa Valley College, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Anderson Ranch Arts Center, 1983-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - School of Art, Kutztown State College, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Long Beach Island Foundation, 1984-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - American Potters Today, 1984-1986; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Chautauqua Institution, 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Temple University, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Kansas City Art Institute, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Friends Seminary, 1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Clay Studio, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - NCECA '85, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Nova Scotia College of Art and Design, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Architecture of the Vessel Symposium, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "University of Arkansas NEA Visiting Artists Forum Series", 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Connecticut Clay Artists, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Alfred College, 1985, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Chicago International New Art Form Exposition, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - NCECA 1986 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Art/Culture/Future: American Craft '86 Conference, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Greenwich House Pottery Workshop, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Lill Street Gallery Fall Education Series, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Plattsburg State University College, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - College Art Association Meetings, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - NCECA '97, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - University of South Carolina, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Harbourfront "International Creators" Lecture Series, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Market House Craft Center, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Symposium: The Case for Clay in Secondary Education, 1987-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Clay in the East IV Symposium, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Hartwick College, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Mercersburg Academy Workshop, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Camden County College, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Baylor University, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - University of Manitoba, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Haystack Mountain School of Crafts, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 48-49)
  - NCECA '89, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Princeton University, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - "Montclair State College Art Forum", 1989 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - University of Michigan School of Art, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Main Line Center of the Arts, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Banff Centre School of Fine Arts, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - "Clayfolk"/Southern Oregon State College, 1989-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Cheltenham Art Centre, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Southern Illinois University Visiting Artist, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - University of Miami, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Chautauqua Institution, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Functional Ceramics Workshop, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - James Renwick Alliance, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - NCECA '90, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Arvada Center for the Arts and Humanities, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Radcliff Ceramics Studio, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Whitemarsh Art Center, 1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Converse College, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Peters Valley Craftsmen, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Arkansas Art Center, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Penland School of Crafts, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Northern Illinois University, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Touchstone Center for Crafts, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Art and Industry Forum, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Nova Scotia College of Art and Design, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Johns Hopkins University School of Continuing Studies, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - NCECA 1991 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Conversations '91, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 78-79)
  - Haystack Mountain School of Crafts, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Massachusetts College of Art, 1991, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Portland School of Art, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - NEA Visual Artist Fellowships/ Crafts Panel, 1991-1992; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - NCECA 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - "American Crafts: The Nation's Collection" Symposium, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Foundations in Art Theory and Education Conference, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Southeastern Massachusetts University, circa 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wayne Art Center, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 92nd Street Y "Artists Visions" Series, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "World Turning Conference", 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - North County Studio Conference, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - NCECA 1993, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Jarrettown Elementary School, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The Craft Experience in Art Education, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Central Bucks High School East Art Day", 1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wood Turning Center "Challenge V", 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Penland School of Crafts, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - Oregon School of Arts and Crafts, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Harding Black Dinner, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - State University of New York, New Paltz, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - University of Northern Iowa, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Corcoran School of Art, 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Cornell University, 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Art Education Association of Indiana Annual Conference, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - The Craft Experience in Art Education II, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Michigan Potters' Association, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Conestoga and Great Valley High Schools, 1994, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Philadelphia College of Art and Design Summer MFA Program, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Anderson Ranch Arts Center, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - 25th Annual Glass Art Society Conference, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
  - The Craft Experience in Art Education III, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Potters Guild of Baltimore, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Penncrest High School, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Pewabic Pottery Exhibit and Workshop, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - University of Oregon, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Westminster Presbyterian Church, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "Fletcher Challenge Ceramic Award", 1995 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Manchester Craftsmen's Guild, 1995, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - William Penn Charter School, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Cheltenham High School, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Penland School of Crafts, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Towson State University, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - "Teaching the Arts: A Dialogue Between Art Educators", 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - "1997 World Turning Conference", 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - 1996 ACC Craft Fair: Baltimore (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Penn Charter Gallery Talk, circa 1996 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Community College of Philadelphia, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - NCECA '96, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Voorhees High School, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - New Hope-Solebury High School, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Abington Friends School, circa 1996 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Princeton University, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Interlocutor's Talk, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Pennsylvania Art Education Association Conference, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - NCECA '98, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Cheltenham Center for the Arts, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Northern Clay Center, 1998, undated (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Appalachian Center for Crafts, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Souderton High School, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 63)
- Writings, 1951-2003, undated; Series 6; 0.6 Linear feet Box 9
  This series houses writings by William Daley and others as well as Daley's personal address lists and calendars. Writings by Daley contain articles, speeches, and other writings. These include artist reviews, autobiographical essays, essays on art, and essays on education. Many files provide several drafts and edited versions with handwritten notations. Also found within the files are related materials including correspondence and clippings of published versions of the artist's writings. Writings by Others contain two articles and one lecture on the art of William Daily, as well as essays on other art topics. Also included are a thesis proposal on ceramics and a master's thesis on the University of the Arts Foundation Program.
  Writings are arranged into three subseries:
  6.1: Writings by Daley, 1951-1999, undated
  6.2: Writings by Others, 1980-2003, undated
  6.3: Address Lists and Calendars, 1968-2000, undated
  - Writings by Daley, 1951-1999, undated; 6.1
    - Articles, "Artist & Teacher," School Arts, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Articles, "Helen Drutt Gallery," Gold Smiths Journal, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Articles, "Celebration of Clay," American Craft, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Articles, NCECA Journal Article, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Articles, "On Drawing", circa 1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Articles, "Recollections From Old Notes and Canted Memories," American Clay Artists, 1988-1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Articles, American Craft Magazine, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Articles, NCECA Conference Newsletter, circa 1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Speeches, Cosmopolitan Club/Trenton Community College, circa 1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, "Aspects of the Apollonian Ideal", 1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Speeches, William Daley: 1990-1980 Gallery Talk, circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Speeches, Notes for NASCAD Graduation Talk, circa 1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Speeches, "Inside/Outside", 1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Other, "The Social Function of Art", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Other, "Wayne Higby", 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Other, Pfannebecker Collection Review, circa 1980 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Other, "A Form Maker's Perception on 'The Case for Clay in Secondary Education'", 1988 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Other, "John Glick", 1989 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Other, Miscellaneous, 1999, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Writings by Others, 1980-2003, undated; 6.2
    - Chambers, Karen S., "A Daley Quest: Seeking the Essence of Clay," The World & I, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Church, Sharon, "Gothic Affinities", 1993 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Fraenkel, Richard, Lecture, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Jepsen, David A., "The Language of Career Development", undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Kokis, George, "The Translucent Object", 1992 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - McTwigan, Michael, "William Daley: In Search of the Vessel," American Craft, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Rapone, Joseph, "The Foundation Program at the University of the Arts: History Methodology, and Ideology," Masters Thesis, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Rattner, Carl, Proposal for "Ranges of meaning in selected contemporary ceramic sculpture manifesting hard and soft form characteristics", 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Address Lists and Calendars, 1968-2000, undated; 6.3
    - Address Lists, 1968, 1994-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
    - Calendars, 1989-1998 (Box 9, Folder 30-36)
- Teaching Files, 1951-1998, undated; Series 7; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  This series contains materials relating to Daley's career as an art professor, primarily at the Philadelphia College of Art from 1965 to 1990. Files on his early career contain correspondence, records, and evaluations. Files pertaining to the Philadelphia College of Art include curriculums, lesson notes, and assignments for several courses. Also found are department mission statements and semester grades. Much of the material was either written by Daley himself or with his colleagues. At the end of the series are several files of general teaching materials, including more notes on ceramics, kiln instructions, and teaching contracts. Items of note in this series are Daley's dismantled ceramics notebook and "Ceramic Shop Notes," as well as materials on a course entitled Concept Development which include many original hand drawn diagrams and illustrations. Files are arranged chronologically by academic institution with general materials arranged chronologically at the end of the series.
  - Alfred University, Ceramics Notebook, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Iowa State Teachers College, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - State University of New York, State Teachers College, 1954-1957 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - University of New Mexico, Guest Professor, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Appointment to Faculty, 1969-1972, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Changes to the Campus, 1966, 1974, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Industrial Design Department, 1972-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Craft Department Mission and Goal Statements, 1986, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Foundation Program Curriculum, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, "Foundation Course Information", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Foundation Program Assignments and Lesson Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Concept Development Curriculum and Diagrams, 1971-1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 48-50)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Dismantled Concept Development Notebook, 1976-1985 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Sophomore Assignments and Lecture Notes, 1983, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Junior Ceramics Assignments, 1970-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Dismantled Junior Ceramics Assignment Notebook, 1980-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Ceramics Senior Projects, 1981-1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)